William Jordan Verbeck Papers
William Jordan Verbeck Papers
1942-1963
Verbeck, William Jordan, 1904-1965.
6 linear ft.
American Army General and career military officer. Collection includes manuscripts, printed material, subject files and correspondence.
3174718
Biographical History
William Jordan Verbeck (1904-1965) was an American military officer who retired with the rank of General. His father, Brig. Gen. William Verbeck, was head of The Manlius School, a military academy in Aurora, New York. During World War II General Verbeck was named commander of the 21st Infantry Division and then chief of staff of the 24th Infantry Division, and during the Korean War he was senior advisor to the G3, Republic of Korea Army. He was decorated numerous times, including the Distinguished Service Medal, Silver Star with oak leaf cluster, Legion of Merit with oak leaf cluster, Bronze Star Medal with valor device and two oak leaf clusters, Army Commendation Medal and Purple Heart with oak leaf cluster.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Jordan Verbeck Papers includes manuscripts, printed material, subject files and correspondence. Please see the box listing below for more details.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has received minimal processing and remains in original order as received.
Subject and Genre Headings
Military history; New York State; Verbeck, William Jordan, 1904-1965.; United States. -- Army -- Officers.; United States. -- Army. -- Infantry Division, 24th.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Alaska -- Aleutian Islands.; United States -- History, Military.; Awards.; Correspondence.; Maps (documents); Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Scripts (documents); Soldiers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William Jordan Verbeck, 1963.
Inventory
- Box listing
  - Script for "The Army Hour," 28N43, plus "Infantry in Alaska" by WJV (Box 1)
  - Address on Aleutian campaign (Box 1)
  - "Emergency foods in the Aleutians", 1943 (Box 1)
  - "Action on Attu", 1943 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks of Japan and Europe (Box 1)
  - Map of Mindanao, award, 2 files of material on Verbeck's service (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous material on the Phillipines (Box 1)
  - Letters from 21st Infantry men received after the war (Box 2)
  - Japan (Box 2)
  - 1955 register of graduates of West Point (Box 3)
  - Photographs of Verbeck (Box 3)
  - Citation from The Manlius School, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Photograph album, Antilles (Box 4)
  - Photographs of China, etc. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, including Manlius Old Boys Bulletin with story by Verbeck (Box 4)
  - A Regiment in Action by Verbeck, 1946; history of 21st Infantry in the Phillipines (Box 5)
  - File on Dutch harbor and Amchitka, Jun 1942-Jan 1943; includes photographs, radiograms, lists of personal unit journal (Box 5)
  - Leyte historical report of the 24th Infantry Division landing team, Oct 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 5)
  - File of "secret" memo re war in Alaska (Box 5)
  - Photograph album, Attu, Massacre Bay (Box 5)
  - File on Aleutians, map of Amchitka (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook of clippings of Alaska, Philippines, Japan (Box 6)
  - Packet of ID cards (Box 6)
  - "The enemy on Kiska" compiled by the Asst. Chief of Staff, includes one volume of illustrative material (Box 6)
  - Photograph albums, Philippines, Escola Superior de Guerra (Box 6)
  - Certificates, awards, orders, decorations, letters re promotion, 1957 (Box 7)
  - The 24th Infantry Division: a brief history, other printed material (Box 8)
  - Army orders file, 1945-1959 (Box 8)
  - Personnel records jacket USA for Verbeck (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia, clippings, some on Fort Devens (Box 9)
  - Public Achievement Award from University of Massachusetts, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Other awards, photographs (Box 9)
  - Children of Yesterday / Valtin, San, on Philippine Islands campaign (Box 10)
  - The Howitzer, 1927; annual of U.S. Corps of Cadets, West Point (Box 10)
  - Photograph album of visits to hospitals and divisions (Box 10)
  - Awards (Oversize 1)
  - List of photographs taken by ?, but no actual photographs (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs of graduates of the first class, National War College, 1946 (Oversize 2)
  - Awards (Oversize 2)